<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eclipse Velocitas – Reference</title>
    <link>/docs/reference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reference on Eclipse Velocitas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 14:24:56 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/docs/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Eclipse Velocitas Overview</title>
      <link>/docs/reference/repository_overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 13:43:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/reference/repository_overview/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/project-overview.svg&#34; alt=&#34;Overview&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Repository&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eclipse-velocitas/vehicle-app-python-template&#34;&gt;vehicle-app-python-template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GitHub Template repository containing an exemplary Vehicle App that uses an exemplary SDK to provide access to vehicle data points and methods. The sample SDK extends the &lt;em&gt;sdv-vehicle-app-python-sdk&lt;/em&gt;. In addition the template repository contains the development environment for Visual Studio Code for a Vehicle App as well as the CI/CD workflows that can be used as blueprint for your own Vehicle App written in Python.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eclipse-velocitas/vehicle-app-python-sdk&#34;&gt;vehicle-app-python-sdk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Provides basis functionality to write an SDK to allow access to vehicle data points and method. This includes publishing &amp;amp; subscribe messaging, talent abstraction, vehicle data model ontology and function-based query &amp;amp; rule support.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eclipse/kuksa.val&#34;&gt;swdc-os-vehicleapi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Provides a vehicle abstraction layer (val) including Vehicle Data Broker, an exemplary CAN Data Feeder as well as a Seat Vehicle Service. The Vehicle Data Broker provides data points available in the vehicle to the Vehicle Apps semantically aligned to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://covesa.github.io/vehicle_signal_specification/&#34;&gt;Vehicle Signal Specification (VSS)&lt;/a&gt;. The CAN Data Feeder is an exemplary implementation that reads in data from the vehicle&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CAN_bus&#34;&gt;CAN bus&lt;/a&gt;, transforms it according to the VSS and feeds it into the Data Broker. The Seat Vehicle Service is an exemplary implementation that illustrates how to interact with in-vehicle components and services via an unified access that is semantically described in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/COVESA/vehicle_service_catalog&#34;&gt;Vehicle Service Catalog (VSC)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eclipse-velocitas/release-documentation-action&#34;&gt;release-documentation-action&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GitHub Action to generate a release documentation from the CI workflow output by rendering it to markdown files so that this can be easily published with GitHub Pages.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eclipse-velocitas/license-check&#34;&gt;license-check&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GitHub Action to collect the licenses of the used components and can be configured to fail with an error message on invalid licenses.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eclipse-velocitas/vehicle-model-generator&#34;&gt;vehicle-model-generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Provides basic functionality to create a vehicle model from the given vspec specification for the target programming language.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
